

Brian France

Front End Developer

Contact

email:

address: 71 Pruyn Hill Rd, Mechanicville, NY 12118 phone: 518-450-3433

briansfrance@gmail.com

Education

Bachelors of Fine Arts: Graphic Design

Sage College of Albany 2008 - 2012

Technical Experience

Software:

Adobe Creative (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign), Sublime Text Editor, Atom, Note Pad ++

Programming Languages:

HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, ¡Query, ReactJS, Vue.js, Vuex, Nuxt.js Vuetify Axios

Summary

Front End Developer with over 6 years experience building user friendly responsive websites and software from concept to final product. Demonstrated the ability to acquire technical knowledge and skills rapidly for the ever evolving front end languages. Proven skills designing and implementing a user interface responsive for desktop, tablet, and mobile friendly devices. Works well in a team environment or on individual projects. Has exceptional communication skills, both written and oral. Is flexible to design changes to ensure client will have the best final product to give to the user.

Qualification Highlights

- · Adept at using Adobe Creative Suite, Photoshop & Illustrator.
- · Have built 5 websites from concept and design to final product from scratch
- · Designed and built the front end of a GE Global Research Center's Digital Thread For Design web application
- · Worked on a fast paced team with ever changing projects on a daily or hourly basis
- · Maintained over 60 client websites on a daily, weekly and monthly basis

Professional Experience

Advanced Information Management

October 2019 - Present

Frontend Developer, UI/UX Designer

- · Work with clients to create concept for software or application
- · Design UI/UX concept with photoshop/Adobe XD
- · Use frontend frameworks and libraries Vue.js, Vuex, Nuxt.js and Vuetify to build software or application off approved design concept
- · Build frontend with responsive design in mind for desktop and mobile
- · Work closely with Backend team to intergrate APIs and end points into frontend UI
- · Quality assurance testing of user interface to ensure the entire user interface was working correctly
- · Deploy frontend code and ui from development through staging using docker

Logic Technology, Inc.

October 2018 - October 2019

Software Engineering Consultant

- Designed the story board and concept for GE Global Research Center's Software Digital Thread For Design(DT4D) User Interface.
- · Directly worked with clients for approval and design theme of DT4D UI
- · Built user experience and user interface for front end of DT4D software using ReactJS
- · Use Fetch in ReactJS to pull from data API's and async end points
- · Work with various ReactJS templates and widgets to create various widgets for front end
- · Built DT4D to be responsive for desktop and mobile devices
- · Work closely with Back End team for pulling APIs and end points
- · Quality assurance testing of user interface to ensure the entire user interface was working correctly
- · Run Python tests with team for testing back end and front end usability

Professional Experience Continued

OOMDO LLC

June 2015 - September 2018

Front End Developer/ Graphic Designer

- · Worked on multiple projects for both graphic design and web design on a daily basis
- Designed and created website assists including but not limited to homepage banner graphics, special price point banners, and landing page graphics
- · Designed and created advertising assets for but not limited to Facebook advertisements, Google ads, and email campaigns
- · Maintained all clients websites for automotive on a daily, weekly, and monthly basis
- · Built from templated automotive host back end sites, over 30 on boarding car dealership client websites
- \cdot Designed and hand coded landing pages for automotive websites that dropped bounce rate from users from 90% to 40%
- · Worked with UI / Graphics team on non automotive client websites for look and feel of user interface
- · Hand coded using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and ¡Query four none automotive websites with design input from UI team and my own design ideas
- · Built non automotive websites to be responsive for desktop and mobile